glasswire.com 2018-12-25

# GlassWire Privacy Policy

## Privacy Frequently Asked Questions

### Can you see or collect my network or graph data?

**No. Your network and graph data stays on your device and is never sent to our GlassWire servers.** We could not see or collect your GlassWire network or graph data even under a court order because we have no access to your network or graph data. Our business model is to sell our premium GlassWire software, not to collect or sell your network data to advertisers.

### Why does GlassWire’s desktop software access the network?

GlassWire’s software for desktop computers checks for software updates that may contain important security fixes along with updating its suspicious host list. GlassWire can block itself from accessing the network, however if you do so then you may not know about important software updates and GlassWire may not alert you if you connect to a suspicious host. GlassWire’s Android app does not ever access the network and has no suspicious host feature.

When installing or uninstalling GlassWire’s desktop software, our installer will contact GlassWire.com so we can know how many installs of our software have occurred. This contact sends your software version number, OS version, and if you’ve installed GlassWire before, along with an anonymized partial IP address and anonymized machine ID to us estimate how many users we have.

### Why does GlassWire for Android request the “phone” permission?

The Android OS requires the “phone” permission for us to see your mobile phone network data. Without this mobile phone permission, it’s impossible for our app to graph your phone’s mobile data. All similar Android apps work the same way. You can learn more details about this [on our Blog](https://blog.glasswire.com/2017/04/18/glasswire-android-permissions/). Of course GlassWire does not make phone calls with your phone and our Android app never accesses the network.

### How does GlassWire make money?

We make money through sales of our software. If you want to support future development of GlassWire you can purchase GlassWire here.

### How do I clear GlassWire's history?

Go to the top left GlassWire menu and turn on GlassWire's "Incognito" feature to keep no history at all, or simply go to GlassWire's top left menu and choose "settings" then click "clear" next to the "clear history" menu. For our Android app you can also clear your history in its settings the same way. Please note we can never see your history at all because it never leaves your device.

### I have a question or request about the EU GDPR, how can I contact you?

If your request concerns a purchase of our software please [contact our billing company Cleverbridge directly](https://www.cleverbridge.com/corporate/contact-us/). Cleverbridge is compliant with the GDPR and can make any GDPR related personal information requests you need. The GlassWire software does not collect personal information, but if you have a GDPR request regarding our websites please contact us directly so we can assist you. If you purchased our software and if you need to do something with your data as allowed by the GDPR please contact Cleverbridge, since they hold any personal data related to GlassWire sales.

### Have more questions or comments?

We welcome your questions and comments. Questions or comments about this privacy policy may be submitted to the address below. Also, please note, if you are a resident of the EU, SecureMix LLC is the controller of your personal data for the purposes of the EU privacy protection law.

**SecureMix LLC**  
PO Box 160611  
Austin, Texas 78716 USA  
Email Contact

### What information does GlassWire collect?

GlassWire collects information from you when you register on our website or forum, email us, place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form or download or install our software.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number or credit card information.

  * GlassWire Installation Process

When installing or uninstalling GlassWire’s desktop software, our installer will contact GlassWire.com so we can know how many installs of our software have occurred. This contact sends your software version number, OS version, and if you’ve installed GlassWire before, along with an anonymized partial IP address and anonymized machine ID to us estimate how many users we have. Our mobile software does not contact GlassWire.com at all because we use the installation stats provided by the Google Play Android store. When uninstalling GlassWire for Windows you have the option to visit our uninstall web page where you have the option to submit the reason that you uninstalled our software.

After installing GlassWire for the PC you may notice on GlassWire's graph that GlassWire itself contacts GlassWire.com around once per day. GlassWire for the desktop checks for software updates that may contain important security fixes and also updates its suspicious host list. GlassWire can block itself from accessing the Internet however if you do so then you may not know about important software updates and your suspicious host list may no longer be up to date. Please note our suspicious host list does not come from GlassWire users. We can never see your network data. Our mobile software does not contact GlassWire.com at all because it has no suspicious host lists and it updates through the Google Play Android store. GlassWire does not collect any personal information through this daily update/software check.

  * GlassWire Activation Codes (Desktop Only)

GlassWire Basic, Pro, Elite and other paid desktop products sometimes use activation codes to unlock GlassWire's paid features. When activating GlassWire Basic, Pro, or Elite the GlassWire software will contact GlassWire.com and check to see if the activation code should be authenticated or not and to see how many machines are using that code. GlassWire keeps an anonymized record of your activation code as related to your computer so it can see how many devices are using your code.

### What does the GlassWire website use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience  
(Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs. For example if we notice a lot of users from France installing GlassWire or visiting our website we may decide to add a French translation of our software.) 
  * To improve our website  
(We continually work to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.) 
  * To improve customer service  
(Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.) 
  * To process transactions  
We may share your information with third parties who deal with secure transaction billing, for example a billing company or credit card company. We don't process transactions on our servers or store billing data there. 
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To keep our website secure and online
  * To send periodic emails  
The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.   
Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email. 
  * If you contact our helpdesk to help with your order, or for technical support.

### How does GlassWire protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place a paid order of our software.

We offer the use of a secure server for all orders of our software. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

Software orders take place with Cleverbridge, our billing company.

### Does GlassWire disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties (like our GlassWire Basic, Pro, and Elite sales billing company) who assist us in operating our website sales, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe the release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety.

If GlassWire’s organization structure changes (for example if we undergo restructuring or are acquired) we may need to move your personal information (if we have any) to a third party related to a business transaction.

GlassWire also has a forum, and our forum allows people to post certain information. If you use the GlassWire forum you can delete all your posts any time by logging in to your account there. Do not share your own personal, or any other personal information in our forum. If you notice personal information is available in our forum please contact us and send us the URL with a removal request.

### Third party website links

Sometimes, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

It's also possible GlassWire forum users may link to third party websites from our forum.

### Cleverbridge Billing

We use a billing company called Cleverbridge to bill our paid desktop software version. We do not collect any credit card information or store it on our own servers. If you do not buy our software you will not use Cleverbridge at all, but if you do buy our software you can review [Cleverbridge's privacy policy here](https://www.cleverbridge.com/corporate/privacy-policy/).

### Mailchimp and Email

We use Mailchimp for our email newsletters. Mailchimp emails are double opt-in and you must grant permission before receiving our email newsletter. To remove your email from Mailchimp click the “unsubscribe” button at the bottom of the email, or contact us so we can help.

We also have email support and you can contact us to request to remove your information from our support system.

Please review [Mailchimp’s privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/).

### GlassWire Forum

Any information that is disclosed in our forums or bulletin boards should be considered public information, and users who message one another may not know each other personally. Users should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in public forums. To request your private information be removed from our forum please contact us with the URL and details of what you would like to be removed.

### Updating or Deleting Information

To update or delete your information with GlassWire, please contact us with the information you want updated or deleted.

### EU Member Rights

If you are located in the EU you have certain privacy rights.

### Retention of Information

We retain information as long as it is needed to provide services for you. Once we find your information is no longer necessary to provide service for you it will be anonymized or deleted sometime in the future.

### Data Processing

GlassWire’s data processing is minimal, occasional, and not on a large scale.

### Privacy by Design

The GlassWire website and software uses privacy by design, as described by the GDPR.

### Access and Porting

Our software does not send us any personal information. For our websites you can request any data be deleted or request available information by contacting us. Our helpdesk usually responds with help within 10-14 business days. Please make the subject of the email “privacy request”.

### Rectify, Restrict, Limit, Delete

You can rectify, restrict, limit, or delete your information related to our forum by logging on to our forum, or you can contact us for help deleting any other website or any other information. Our helpdesk usually responds with help within 15 business days. There is also a possibility under certain circumstances for the individual to invoke binding arbitration.

### Object

You can contact us to object to our website using your information. Please contact us so we can assist you.

### Revoke Consent

Where you provided consent before, you can revoke your consent by contacting us. If consent is revoked you should stop using our website and software.

### Comments & Concerns

If you have concerns about your data you have the right to contact your local supervisory authority.

### Data Protection Officer

GlassWire has appointed a data protection officer. Please email any of our contact page email addresses with the subject “data protection officer” to contact them. Or please mail SecureMix LLC, PO Box 160611, Austin, Texas 78716 USA to request your personal information, update your personal information, or delete data that our business has no use for, request that we stop processing your data.

### GDPR Guidelines

Our company has made all of our company decision makers aware of the GDPR guidelines and our staff has been trained to be aware of data protection.

### GDPR Data Transfers

We only transfer personal information outside of the EU to countries that offer an appropriate level of protection.

### FTC

Our organization is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and/ or the Department of Transportation.

### VirusTotal

GlassWire includes the VirusTotal API which is turned off by default.  
Learn more about VirusTotal here: <https://support.virustotal.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002126889-How-it-works>. VirusTotal checks suspicious samples with several antivirus solutions and helps antivirus labs by forwarding them the malware they fail to detect. Please review the VirusTotal Terms of Service and [Privacy Policy](https://support.virustotal.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002168385-Privacy-Policy) before using the VirusTotal API setting within GlassWire. Both policies are linked to from within the GlassWire software. 

### Company and Subsidiaries

SecureMix LLC is our organization’s main USA Texas based entity, but we also do business under the name “GlassWire” (a registered USA Trademark and also a USA entity).

### Consent

To use our website or software, you must be 18 or older, and you consent to our online privacy policy and software license agreement/EULA.

Last Updated: September 19, 2018 – Now we collect even less data. No Google Analytics.
